[
    {
        "question": "Which organisation releases the Annual Status of Education Report (ASER) 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Sarvpratham Foundation ",
            "Pratham Foundation ",
            "Nanhi jaan Foundation ",
            "Pehel Foundation "
        ],
        "answer": "Pratham Foundation ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Department for Promotion of Industry and Internal Trade (DPIIT) and JKEDI has signed a MoU to strengthen startup ecosystem in which state/UT?",
        "options": [
            "Ladakh  ",
            "Jammu and Kashmir  ",
            "Kerala  ",
            "Maharashtra "
        ],
        "answer": "Jammu and Kashmir  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which entity has launched iSPOT Portal for Reporting Technical Glitches?",
        "options": [
            "RBI ",
            "SEBI ",
            "SIDBI  ",
            "IRDAI "
        ],
        "answer": "SEBI ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vedanta Group will invest Rs 1 lakh crore for an integrated aluminium complex and an aluminium park in which state?",
        "options": [
            "Assam ",
            "Karnataka  ",
            "Telangana  ",
            "Odisha "
        ],
        "answer": "Odisha ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which companies has received a significant order to build Uzbekistan's first AI-enabled and sustainable 10-Megawatt data centre in Tashkent?",
        "options": [
            "Larsen & Toubro  ",
            "Reliance industries  ",
            "Adani Power  ",
            "Wipro technologies "
        ],
        "answer": "Larsen & Toubro  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which entity has rejected the competing open offer for Religare Enterprises by Florida, US-based investor Digivijay 'Danny' Gaekwad?",
        "options": [
            "RBI ",
            "SEBI ",
            "CCI ",
            "IRDAI "
        ],
        "answer": "SEBI ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ministry of Finance has notified that penal charges imposed by banks and non-banking financial companies (NBFCs) for non-compliance with loan terms will not attract an what per cent goods and services tax (GST)?",
        "options": [
            "5% ",
            "12% ",
            "18% ",
            "28% "
        ],
        "answer": "18% ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'world's biggest iceberg', \"____\", which is more than twice the size of London, is drifting toward South Georgia Island.",
        "options": [
            "K32g iceberg ",
            "P96s iceberg ",
            "N18y iceberg ",
            "A23a iceberg "
        ],
        "answer": "A23a iceberg ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "India has signed an agreement with which country to amend their taxation treaty \u2014 Double Taxation Avoidance Agreement (DTA",
        "options": [
            "\u2014 in an attempt to align it with international standards on cross-",
            "Kuwait  ",
            "Iran ",
            "Qatar  ",
            "Oman "
        ],
        "answer": "Qatar  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Ministry of Micro, Small, and Medium Enterprises (MSME) has launched the MSME Trade Enablement and Marketing (TEAM) initiative to empower small businesses in adopting digital commerce With a sanctioned budget of Rs_.",
        "options": [
            "Rs 512.35 crore  ",
            "Rs 417.35 crore  ",
            "Rs 277.35 crore  ",
            "Rs 318.35 crore "
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 277.35 crore  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company to set up India\u2019s first exclusive electric two-wheeler plant by 2028?",
        "options": [
            "Hero MotoCorp ",
            "Bajaj Auto ",
            "TVS Motor ",
            "Honda "
        ],
        "answer": "Honda ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following has approved the proposed acquisition of up to 72.64% shareholding in ITD Cementation India Limited by Renew Exim DMCC?",
        "options": [
            "Reserve Bank of India (RBI)  ",
            "Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) ",
            "Competition Commission of India (CCI) ",
            "Confederation of Indian Industry (CII) "
        ],
        "answer": "Competition Commission of India (CCI) ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "India's digital economy aims for a 20% national income contribution by which year?",
        "options": [
            "2029-30 ",
            "2030-31 ",
            "2034-35 ",
            "2039-40 "
        ],
        "answer": "2029-30 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state has becomes first North East State to sign MoU with Bhashini for Multi-lingual Governance?",
        "options": [
            "Nagaland  ",
            "Tripura  ",
            "Manipur  ",
            "Meghalaya "
        ],
        "answer": "Tripura  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been reappointed as the MD & CEO of IDBI Bank for a three-year ?",
        "options": [
            "Rakesh Sharma ",
            "Sunil Mehta ",
            "Sanjiv Chadha ",
            "Aditya Puri "
        ],
        "answer": "Rakesh Sharma ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the mascot of the 38th Summer National Games 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Mauli ",
            "Chinkara ",
            "Serow ",
            "Sangai "
        ],
        "answer": "Mauli ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alexander Lukashenko has been re-elected as the President of which country for the record seventh time?",
        "options": [
            "Israel  ",
            "Oman ",
            "Kuwait  ",
            "Belarus "
        ],
        "answer": "Belarus ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lezim dance, recently in news, is mainly performed in:",
        "options": [
            "Kerala ",
            "Rajasthan ",
            "Bihar ",
            "Maharashtra "
        ],
        "answer": "Maharashtra ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Asian Waterbird Census:  1. It supports the conservation and management of wetlands and waterbirds worldwide.  2. It is part of International Waterbird Census conducted annually.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the duration of the recently approved National Critical Mineral Mission?",
        "options": [
            "5 years ",
            "7 years  ",
            "3 years  ",
            "2 years "
        ],
        "answer": "7 years  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Union ministry is the nodal body for implementing the recently approved National Critical Mineral Mission?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Chemicals and Fertilizers ",
            "Ministry of Power ",
            "Ministry of Heavy Industries ",
            "Ministry of Mines "
        ],
        "answer": "Ministry of Mines ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the total outlay for the recently approved National Critical Mineral Mission?",
        "options": [
            "Rs 34,300 crore ",
            "Rs 16,200 crore ",
            "Rs 24,500 crore ",
            "Rs 44,100 crore "
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 34,300 crore ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a Critical Minerals?",
        "options": [
            "Phosphate ",
            "Antimony ",
            "Rhenium ",
            "Asbestos "
        ],
        "answer": "Asbestos ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Digital Payments Index (DPI) for September 2024 as per RBI data?",
        "options": [
            "465.33 ",
            "304.06 ",
            "512.44 ",
            "458.15 "
        ],
        "answer": "465.33 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which parameter has the highest weight in the RBI DPI?",
        "options": [
            "Payment Enablers ",
            "Payment Performance ",
            "Consumer Centricity ",
            "Payment Infrastructure "
        ],
        "answer": "Payment Performance ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has become India's first steel company to develop pipes for hydrogen transportation?",
        "options": [
            "JSW Steel  ",
            "Tata Steel ",
            "Steel Authority of India Ltd ",
            "Jindal Steel And Power "
        ],
        "answer": "Tata Steel ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Mutual Credit Guarantee Scheme for micro, small and medium enterprises (MCGS-MSMEs):  1. It aims at providing 60 per cent guarantee coverage by National Credit Guarantee Trustee Company Limited (NCGTC) to Member Lending Institutions.  2. Under this scheme a borrower should be an MSME with valid Udyam Registration Number.  3. It provides a loan guarantee up to Rs 100 crore  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "to Member Lending Institutions. ",
            "1 and 2 only ",
            "2 and 3 only ",
            "1, 2 and 3 ",
            "None "
        ],
        "answer": "2 and 3 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to MSME Trade Enablement and Marketing (TEAM) Initiative, consider the following:  1. It has been launched under the \"Raising and Accelerating MSME Productivity (RAMP)\" Programme.  2. It is an initiative in partnership with the Open Network for Digital Commerce (ONDC).  3. It will focus on onboarding 5 lakh micro and small enterprises, with 50 per cent of these being SC/ST led businesses.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            ". ",
            "1 and 2 only ",
            "2 and 3 only ",
            "1, 2 and 3 ",
            "None "
        ],
        "answer": ". ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state Tableaux has won the best Tableaux award of the 2025 Republic Day?",
        "options": [
            "Gujarat  ",
            "Tripura  ",
            "Andhra Pradesh  ",
            "Uttar Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Uttar Pradesh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state Tableaux has won the best Tableaux award of the 2025 Republic Day In the Popular Choice category?",
        "options": [
            "Uttarakhand  ",
            "Uttar Pradesh  ",
            "Gujarat  ",
            "Andhra Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Gujarat  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ministry of the government of India administers the award given to the best Marching Contingent and Tableaux at the Republic Day Parade?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Culture ",
            "Ministry of Defence ",
            "Ministry of Tribal Affairs ",
            "Ministry of Textiles "
        ],
        "answer": "Ministry of Defence ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country signed five MoUs with India to strengthen bilateral ties in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Malaysia ",
            "Thailand ",
            "Indonesia ",
            "Philippines "
        ],
        "answer": "Indonesia ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian institution ranked 99th in computer science in THE World Rankings 2025, becoming the first Indian institution to enter the global top 100 for this subject?",
        "options": [
            "IISc Bengaluru ",
            "IIT Bombay ",
            "IIT Delhi ",
            "IIT Madras "
        ],
        "answer": "IISc Bengaluru ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization has launched the IFTV platform nationwide in partnership with Skypro and PlayboxTV?",
        "options": [
            "Jio ",
            "Airtel ",
            "Vi ",
            "BSNL "
        ],
        "answer": "BSNL ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]